Friends, family,
we're gathered to celebrate...
우리는 오늘 이 자리에 모여
...the joyous union of Ross and Emily.
로스와 에밀리의 복된 만남을
축복하고자 합니다
Now, Ross, repeat after me.
로스, 절 따라하세요
"l, Ross."
나 로스는
I, Ross.
"Take thee, Emily."
이 사람 에밀리를
Take thee, Rachel.
이 사람 레이첼을
에밀리!
에, 에밀리...
계속해도 될까요?
Shall I go on?
He said, "Rachel," right?
지금 레이첼이라고 했죠?
내가 올라가야 될까요?
Do you think I should go up there?
Yes. Yes. Do go on.
네, 계속하세요
다시 시작하는 게 좋겠군요
I think we'd better start again.
네
로스, 날 따라하세요
Repeat after me.
"l, Ross."
나 로스는
I, Ross.
나 로스는...
"Take thee, Emily."
이 사람 에밀리를!
Take thee, Emily.
이 사람 에밀리를...
어디 딴 사람이 또 있나?
Like there'd be anybody else.
"As my lawfully wedded wife,
in sickness and in health...
죽음이 둘을 갈라놓을 때까지
평생 사랑할 것을 맹세합니다
...till death parts us."
As my lawfully wedded wife,
in sickness and in health...
죽음이 둘을 갈라놓을 때까지
평생 사랑할 것을 맹세합니다
...until death parts us.
Really, I do. Emily.
정말이야
에밀리를!
Do you have the rings?
반지 있나요?
에밀리
Place this ring on Ross' finger...
이 반지를 로스에게 끼워
영원한 사랑을 서약하세요
...as a symbol of
your bond everlasting.
아야!
로스, 이 반지를
에밀리의 손에 끼워
Ross, place this ring...
...on Emily's hand as a symbol...
영원히 지속될
사랑을 증명하세요
...of the love that
encircles you forever.
Happy to.
기꺼이
로스와 에밀리의 맹세에 따라
They have made
their declarations...
...and it gives me great pleasure
to declare them husband and wife.
기쁜 마음으로 두 사람이
부부가 되었음을 선언합니다
신부에게 키스하세요
You may kiss the bride.
This is worse than when
he married the lesbian.
레즈비언이랑 결혼할 때보다
더 심각하군요
Just keep smiling.
계속 웃기나 해
알았어
Well, that went well.
대충 잘 끝났네요 뭐
까딱했으면 누구 하나
총 맞을 뻔했거든
It could've been worse.
He could've shot her.
That was pretty funny, wasn't it?
거 참 재미있네, 그지?
The One After Ross Says "Rachel"
You spoiled everything!
It's a nightmare!
자기 때문에 다 망쳤어
이건 악몽이야
My friends and family are out there!
How can I face them?
친구들이랑 가족들 앞에서
어떻게 이럴 수가 있어
No matter what happens with them...
로스랑 에밀리가 어떻게 되든
케이크는 먹을 수 있는 거지?
...we still get cake, right?
그래, 천천히 하라고
난 밖에 있을게
That's all right. You take your time.
I'll be right out here.
She's just fixing her makeup.
화장을 좀 고친다나?
I hate you!
자기를 증오해
And I love you!
난 자길 사랑해!
결정적인 순간에
이름이 헛 나왔구나
A bad time
to say the wrong name, huh?
That's true. Thanks, Dad.
네, 감사합니다, 아버님
춤들 안 추나요?
People should be dancing.
이건 파티예요
뭐하고 있어요?
This is a party! Come on!
조이, 춤춰!
Joey! Dance!
Yes, Waltham lnteriors.
네, 월섬 인테리어입니다
여보세요, 전 로스 겔러의
주치의 필란지 박사예요
This is Ross Geller's
personal physician, Dr. Filangie.
Who?
누구요?
로스가 두통약을 두고 갔더군요
I discovered that Ross forgot
to take his brain medicine.
Without it, in the brain of Ross...
그게 없으면 머리가 아파서
여자들의 이름이 뒤섞여요
...women's names are interchangeable.
Through no fault of his own.
본인 잘못이 아니에요
Oh, my God! Phoebe.
이런, 피비
No, not Phoebe. Dr. Filangie.
피비가 아니라
닥터 필란지예요
Oh, no! You have it too!
댁도 그런 증상이 있군요
What kind of bitch hangs up
on a doctor?
의사 전화를 끊는
망할 년도 다 있네
나야
그래
I hope you don't take this
the wrong way...
이런 말 오해할지도 모르지만
...but I know we had plans
to meet up tonight.
오늘밤에 만나기로 한 거...
I'm worried about what it
might do to our friendship.
우리 우정에 금가면
어쩌나 걱정스러워
I know.
알아
- 어쩌다 이렇게 됐지?
- 일곱 번이나!
-How could we have let this happen?
-Seven times!
You know, look.
We were away.
알다시피 여긴
우리나라가 아니잖아
In a foreign, romantic country.
로맨틱한 남의 나라지
I blame London.
런던 때문이야
Bad London!
나쁜 런던!
So look...
어쨌든...
...while we're still in London,
we can keep doing it, right?
런던에 있는 동안은
계속해도 괜찮겠지?
Well, I don't see that
we have a choice.
다른 수가 없잖아
But when we're back home,
we don't do it.
하지만 돌아가면
끝내는 거야
Only here.
여기서만!
You know, I saw
a wine cellar downstairs.
지하에 포도주 창고가 있던데
I'll meet you there in two minutes.
- 2분 후에 거기서 봐
- 좋지!
Mon? I gotta ask you something.
모니카, 물어볼 게 있어
Now?
지금?
Ross said my name.
I can't just pretend it didn't happen.
로스가 내 이름을 말했는데
모르는 척해도 되는 걸까?
I don't know.
모르겠다
Monica, what should I do?
난 어떡하면 좋지?
그냥 옳은 행동을 해
Just do the right thing.
What?
뭘?
Tow the line! Thread the needle!
Think outside the box!
뭐든 해봐, 좋을 대로
뒤집어서 생각하라고
잠깐, 로스한테 그게
무슨 뜻인지 물어볼래
I'll talk to Ross
about what he thinks it meant.
이러지 마
레이첼, 안 돼
Wait! Rachel, no.
He's married.
오빠는 결혼했어
Married.
유부남이라고
If you don't realize that,
I can't help you.
그걸 깨닫지 못하면
내가 도와줄 수 없어
Okay. You're right.
그래, 맞아
You're right.
You can't help me.
맞는 말이야
넌 못 도와줘
Jack, is it all our fault?
Were we bad parents?
잭, 이게 우리 잘못인가요?
우리가 형편없는 부모예요?
아무렴
Who serves steak
when there's no place to sit?
앉을 자리도 없는데
누가 스테이크를 냈어
How are you supposed to eat this?
이걸 어떻게 먹냐고
Hey, what's up?
왜 그러세요?
You and me, next dance?
저랑 한 곡 추실까요?
미안하지만 맨 정신엔 못 춰
Sorry, dear,
I only dance when I'm drunk.
Want me to get you something?
뭐 좀 갖다드려요?
We were supposed to meet.
어디 갔었어
지하실로 오라며
-Forget it. That's off.
-Why?
- 잊어버려, 끝났어
- 왜?
다음엔 포도주 창고를 보시죠
The next tour of the wine cellar...
...will commence in two minutes.
2분 후부터 시작됩니다...
Joey, what are you doing?
조이, 이게 무슨 짓이야
You promised, no meat
till Phoebe has the babies.
고기 안 먹기로
피비랑 약속했잖아
여긴 다른 나라니까
상관없을 것 같아서
We're in another country,
so it doesn't count.
-True.
-He's got a point.
- 그렇구나
- 일리 있는 말씀
로스
그래
I'm sorry things aren't working out.
일이 이렇게 돼서 유감이다
아냐...
It could be better.
It'll be okay, right?
별일 아니니까 괜찮아지겠지
당연하지, 금방 잊을 거야
겨우 내 이름 말한 건데 뭐
Oh, yeah! Of course.
She'll get over this.
So you said my name.
You just said it
because you saw me there.
그 자리에서 날 봐서 그랬겠지
서커스 광을 봤다면
이랬을 거야
If you'd seen a circus freak,
you would've said:
"l take thee, Circus Freak."
'이 사람 서커스 광을'
그냥 실수 좀 한 건데
무슨 의미가 있나 뭐
It didn't mean anything.
It's a mistake.
Right?
- 안 그래?
- 그럼, 무슨 의미가 있겠어
Oh, no! Of course
it didn't mean anything.
하지만 에밀리 마음도 이해해
I can understand why Emily
thought it meant something...
- 그게 너였으니까
- 맞아
...because it was you.
그래도 절대 아냐!
아니라고!
But it absolutely didn't.
It didn't! It didn't!
The band's ready
for your first dance with Emily.
로스, 밴드가 기다려
신부랑 춤을 춰야지
Oh! The band's ready!
오! 밴드가 기다리는구나
We've got to do what the band says.
I don't care about the stupid band!
밴드가 시키는 대로 하라고?
바보 같은 밴드는 신경 안 써!
You spit on me, man!
침 튀기잖아
I'm sorry.
미안하다
Emily is taking kind of a long time.
너무 오래 있는 거 아냐?
When I locked myself up
at my wedding...
나도 결혼식 때
화장실 문을 잠그고
...I was trying to pop
the window out of the frame.
- 유리창을 깨려고 했지
- 맞아
삼십육계 줄행랑, 알아?
Get the hell out of there.
You know?
에밀리?
에밀리!
I'm coming in!
나 들어간다
Oh, look at that.
Same thing.
이걸 봐, 똑같아
In the middle of everything,
if I scream, "Yippee!" just ignore me.
내가 중간에 '야호! '
이래도 무시해버려
-Oh, my God! Rachel!
-Oh, hello, Rachel.
- 엄마야, 레이첼
- 안녕, 레이첼?
Ross said my name.
로스가 내 이름을 말했어
알았어? 내 이름이라고
Okay? My name!
Ross said my name up there.
거기서 내 이름을 말한 건
아직 날 사랑한다는 뜻이야
That obviously means
he still loves me!
Don't believe me.
I know I'm right.
안 믿어줘도 좋지만
내 생각이 맞아
Do you guys want to go
and get a drink?
내려가서 한잔할까?
Yes, we do.
그거 좋지
But we have to change first.
하지만 옷부터 갈아입고
Yes, I want to change.
그래, 나도 갈아입을래
-Go get a table.
-We'll only be five minutes.
가서 테이블 맡아 놔
- 5분 후에 갈게
- 15분!
Fifteen minutes.
좋아
여보세요?
Oh, Phoebe! It's Phoebe!
오, 피비
피비야
-Oh, hey, hey.
-Oh, great.
- 그렇구나
- 반가워라
안녕?
So, what happened?
어떻게 됐어
Well, Ross said my name.
로스가 내 이름을 말했어
But I don't think
that means anything.
그게 무슨 의미가
있는 건 아닐 텐데
객관적으로 한번 생각해보자
Let's look at this objectively.
중3때야, 알아?
Ninth grade, right?
The obsession starts.
집착의 시작이었지
이듬해 여름, 투피스 입은 날
처음 보고 집착이 커져 갔어
Then he sees me in
a two-piece for the first time.
His obsession begins to grow, right?
Why don't we go change in my room?
- 내 방에서 갈아입는 건 어때
- 내 옷은...
My clothes are....
Wow, you look
와우, 너 정말...
No time for that.
- 시간 없어
- 알았어
Hey, dude! Let me in!
I got a girl out here!
야, 좀 들어가자
여자 데려왔어
I got a girl in here!
나도 여자 있어
No, you don't.
I saw you go in with Monica.
모니카랑 들어가던데
무슨 소리야
Well, we're hanging out.
우린 좀 쉴 거야
Which one of us will be
having sex in there? Me or you?
지금 그 방에서 섹스 할
사람이 너냐, 나냐?
그럼 너라고 말해야겠지
I suppose I would
have to say you.
-What if we're watching a movie?
-Which we are!
영화 보고 있다면 어떡할래
그래, 맞아
벌써 돈도 냈어
'마이 자이언트'
And we've paid for it.
It's My Giant.
My Giant?
마이 자이언트?
나 그 영화 진짜 좋아해
I love that movie!
Think this is okay?
정말 이래도 괜찮을까?
Well, Ross and Emily
aren't going to use it.
로스하고 에밀리는
안 쓸 거니까
Oh, it's so beautiful!
정말 예쁘다
I don't feel right about this.
이럼 안 될 것 같다
모, 모, 모니카
This is the honeymoon suite.
여긴 허니문 스위트야
섹스를 기대하는 방이라고
The room expects sex.
섹스를 하지 않으면
이 방이 실망할 거야
The room would be disappointed
if it didn't get sex.
All the other honeymoon suites
would think it was a loser.
다른 허니문 스위트들이
얘를 바보라고 놀리겠지
- 좋아
- 그럼
에밀리?
Nope! Not under here!
아니, 여긴 없는데?
-You didn't find her?
-I've looked everywhere.
- 못 찾았어?
- 응, 다 뒤져봤는데
You couldn't have,
or you would've found her.
다 뒤져봤으면
분명 찾았을 거야
그래, 계속 찾아봐
-Keep looking!
-Yeah! For about 30 minutes?
- 맞아, 30분 정도?
- 아니면 45분?
Or 45?
In 45 minutes,
you could find her twice.
45분이면 신부 두 번도 찾겠다
For all I know, she's trying to find me
but couldn't, because I kept moving.
설사 에밀리가 날 찾으려 해도
내가 계속 돌아다니면 못 찾지
From now on,
I'm staying in one place.
이제 한 자리에만 있을래
Right here.
바로 여기
-It's getting late.
-We're going to go.
- 시간이 늦었네
- 우린 갈게
저기...
Do you guys mind staying here
for a while?
잠깐 여기 있으면 안 될까?
내일 아침 일찍
비행기 타야 돼
We've got to get up early
and catch that plane.
엄청 큰 비행기거든
Yeah, it's a very large plane.
That's cool.
알았어
But we'll stay here with you.
하지만 같이 있을게
Thanks, guys!
고맙다, 얘들아
I really appreciate this,
but you don't need to rub my butt.
고맙긴 한데
엉덩이는 왜 더듬나
We have to leave in an hour.
우린 한 시간 후에
뉴욕으로 가야 돼
I know. I've been looking
at those doors.
알아, 내가 문을 살펴봤는데
방음은 잘되는 것 같더라
They look pretty soundproof,
don't you think?
We can't do that.
That's insane.
이건 안 돼, 미친 짓이야
I mean, A, he could wake up.
And B, you know...
첫째, 로스가 깨잖아
둘째, 알지?
해보자고
...Iet's go for it.
에밀리? 에밀리...
- 에밀리!
- 아니라네
Nope.
-She's not with us.
-We've come for her things.
같이 왔을 거란
기대는 말게
소지품 가지러 왔네
Where is she?
에밀리 어디 있죠?
숨어있네
She's in hiding. She's humiliated.
She doesn't want to see you again.
그런 수치를 당하고
자넬 또 보고 싶겠나?
We're very sad that it didn't work out
between you and Emily, monkey.
일이 이렇게 돼서
나도 유감이야
원숭이...
But I think you're
absolutely delicious!
하지만 자네 참 구미가 당겨
Excuse me,
I'm standing right here.
실례지만 저 지금
여기 서있는데요?
Oh, yes.
네, 거기 계셨군요
There you are.
Hurry up! Get some!
There's a whole cart outside.
얘들아, 빨리 나가서
이거 좀 집어와
Goodbye, Geller.
잘 있게
Now, hold on. Hold on.
잠깐 기다려보세요
Your daughter and I are supposed
to leave tonight for our honeymoon.
전 오늘밤 따님과
신혼여행 떠날 사람입니다
Tell her I'll be at that airport,
and I hope she will too.
공항에 나가 있을 테니까
꼭 나오라고 전해주십시오
I said Rachel's name,
but it didn't mean anything.
네, 제가 이름을 잘못 말했지만
레이첼은 그냥 친구일 뿐이에요
She's just a friend.
전 에밀리를 사랑합니다
Tell Emily I love her and...
...I can't imagine spending my life
with anyone else.
다른 사람과 여생을
보내는 건 상상할 수 없어요
Please, promise me that
you'll tell her that.
꼭 전해주실 거라
믿어도 되겠습니까?
All right, I'll tell her.
그래, 전해주지
Come on, bugger face!
가자고, 여편네
Call me.
전화해
You spend your life in the bathroom.
Why do you never go out the window?
똥간에서 죽치고 사는 여자가
왜 창문으로 내빼지 않고
오히려 이게 잘된 일인지도 몰라
Maybe it's best we never
got to do it again.
Yeah, it kind of makes
that one night special.
그럼으로써 하룻밤의
의미는 더욱 깊어지고
Technically, we still are
over international waters.
정확히 말하면 우린
아직 공해 상에 있어
I'm going to the bathroom.
Maybe I'll see you there?
난 화장실 갈 건데
거기서 볼 수 있을까?
그래
Can I ask you something?
뭐 하나 물어보자
안 돼
Felicity and I watched
My Giant. And I thought:
내가 펠리시티랑
마이 자이언트 본 거 알지?
난 그 거인보다 훌륭한
배우가 못될 거 같아
"I'll never be as good an actor
as that giant."
연기로 성공하긴 틀린 걸까?
Do you think I'm wasting my life
with this acting thing?
아니
The giant's five years
younger than me.
거인은 나보다 5살 밑인데
나도 그렇게 될 수 있겠어?
You think I'll ever get there?
그럼
-Thanks, man.
-Okay, man.
- 고맙다
- 별말씀을
But what about how much
taller he is than me?
도대체 나보다 얼마나 크지?
I mean, there's no way
I can make myself taller now.
내가 여기서 더
자랄 순 없겠지만
과학이 날로 발전하고 있잖아
어쨌거나 챈들러...
Who knows what science will
come up with in the future...
...but what if I die an unsuccessful,
regular-size man?
실패한 보통 사이즈의
남자로 죽으면 어떡하냐고
You've been in the
bathroom for a half-hour.
너 왔니?
화장실에 30분이나 있어?
I know!
알아
Had the beef tips, huh?
소갈비 먹었구나
- 왔구나!
- 피비!
You ate meat!
너 고기 먹었지!
You had sex!
여긴 섹스 했고!
No, we didn't.
안 했어
I know you didn't.
I was talking about Monica.
네가 아니라 모니카 말이야
I did not have sex.
누가 섹스를 했다고
This pregnancy is throwing me all off
and making me fat.
임신해서 정신이 없다
살도 엄청 찌고
-I'll say hi to the chick and duck.
-Me too!
- 병아리랑 오리한테 인사해야지
- 나도
Why would you need to?
You've been feeding them.
나흘 동안 밥 준 사람이
인사는 무슨
Oh, right.
Maybe I'll just go home.
오, 그렇구나
집에나 가야겠다
We certainly are alone.
우리 둘만 남았네
Good thing we have that
"not New York" rule.
뉴욕에선 안 된다고
한 게 다행이지
맞아
저기, 얘기가
나왔으니 말인데...
Listen, since we're on that subject...
이 말을 하고 싶었어
...I just wanted to tell you that....
I was going through
a hard time in London...
나 런던에서 좀 힘들었거든
...with my brother getting married and
that guy thinking I was Ross' mother.
오빠가 결혼하고
졸지에 난 오빠 엄마가 되고
그랬지
어쨌든 그날 밤은 참 좋았어
Well, anyway, I just....
That night meant a lot to me.
And I'm trying to say thanks.
다 네 덕분이야
You know, that night
meant a lot to me too.
그날 밤은 나도 좋았어
It wasn't because I was
in a bad place or anything.
그냥 낯선 데라서
좋았던 게 아니라
It just meant a lot because
you're really hot.
네가 정말 화끈해서
Is that okay?
괜찮아?
That's okay.
그럼
And I'm cute too?
나도 좀 귀여웠고
And you're cute too!
- 정말 귀여웠어
- 고맙다
Thank you.
All right, I gotta go unpack.
- 이제 짐이나 풀어야지
- 그래
안녕
I'm still on London time.
Does that count?
내 몸은 아직 런던 시간에 맞춰
돌아가는데 그것도 쳐주나?
-Oh, that counts!
-Oh, good!
- 당연히 쳐주지
- 좋았어
레이첼
- 레이첼
- 이런
What are you doing here?
여긴 웬일이야?
I've been on standby for
a flight home for hours.
몇 시간째 빈자리 나길
기다리고 있었어
에밀리 못 찾았구나
So no sign of Emily?
Not yet.
아직
그래...
When do you have to leave?
언제 떠나기로 했어?
This is the last call
for flight 1066 to A thens.
아테네 행 1066편
마지막 안내방송입니다
The last call.
Pretty soon, I guess.
- 별로 안 남은 것 같네
- 그래
I'm sorry.
어쩜 좋니
I don't understand.
이해를 못하겠어
너무 하는 거 아냐?
How could she do this?
에밀리가 올 거라고
믿는다면 내가 바보일까?
Am I a complete idiot for
thinking she'd actually show up?
아니, 넌 바보가 아냐
You're not an idiot, Ross.
You're a guy very much in love.
- 사랑에 빠진 남자일 뿐이지
- 그게 그거구만 뭐
Same difference.
아테네 행 1066편 승객 분들은
즉시 탑승해주십시오
All passengers for flight 1066
to Athens should now be onboard.
I get it!
알아들었어!
Well, that's that.
이걸로 끝났군
No, you know what?
그럴 게 아니라
너 혼자라도 가
I think you should go.
뭐?
I think you should go...
그래, 혼자 가는 게 좋겠어
멀리 떨어져서 생각을 정리해
...by yourself.
Get some distance.
Clear your head.
It would be really good.
나쁠 거 없잖아
I don't know.
글쎄, 난...
그게 너한테 이롭다니까
Come on.
It would be really good for you.
하긴...
I could do that.
- 못할 거야 없지만
- 그럼!
I can't even believe her.
이건 너무 심했어
알았어, 갈 거야
You know what?
I am going to go.
-Good.
-Why not?
- 잘 생각했어
- 왜 못 가
- 맞아
- 좋아...
-Right?
-Right.
Thanks.
고마워
I'll see you back at home.
그래, 집에서 봐
If I ever get a flight out of here.
나도 빈자리만 나면
여길 뜰 거야
저기...
- 아냐...
- 왜, 뭔데 그래
What? Wait, what?
Why don't you come?
같이 갈래?
I mean, I have two tickets.
Why not?
티켓도 두 장인데
못 갈 거 없지
Well, I don't know, Ross.
Really?
말도 안 되는 소릴...
진심이야?
Yeah. It'd be great.
I mean, you can....
그래, 좋잖아
넌 해변에서 일광욕하고
You can lay on the beach...
...and I can cry over
my failed marriage.
난 실패한 결혼을
한탄하며 통곡하고
나 농담 잘하지?
You see how I make jokes?
Really. I mean....
진심이야
지금은 친구가 필요해
I could use a friend.
Oh, wow. Maybe.
글쎄, 어떡할까...
Yes, I can do that!
- 그래, 갈 수 있어
- 잘 생각했어
-Cool.
-All right, cool.
- 좋아
- 가자
여기요
그리스로 가는 거야
Okay, we're going to Greece.
I forgot my jacket!
이런, 재킷을 잊었어
- 잠깐, 그럼...
- 기다리라고 해
Well, you tell them to wait.
알았어
- 기다리세요!
- 좋았어
Wait! Wait!
에밀리...
아니, 아니, 아니...
아니라니깐...
아냐! 아니라고!
젠장, 에밀리!
I'll have a glass of Merlot...
네, 전 메를로 한 잔
...and he'll have
a wine spritzer.
그리고 이쪽은 백포도주 한 잔
Look!
The airport's moving.
이런, 공항이 움직이네?
Are we moving?
이게 움직이잖아
Are we?
Why are we moving?
우리가 움직여요?
왜 움직이죠?
저기...
Does the captain know
that we're moving?
기장님은 이 사실을
알고 있나요?
맙소사
Oh, my gosh!
일났네